Teri Raftery Senior Business Analyst Consultant

78 Lavander Road | Barkhamsted, Connecticut 06063 | Cell: 860.712.9035 | Email: teriraf@charter.net

SUMMARY

A results-focused Senior Business Consultant with proven successes leading and participating in a broad range of strategic and tactical initiatives. Over twenty years extensive experience in all phases of a project life cycle which includes expert analytical, problem solving, time management and documentation skills.

SPECIALTIES

- Lean Six Sigma Green Belt Certified
- Detailed analysis
- Requirement elicitation
- Problem solving/decision making
- Process Improvement
- Strategic planning
- Organizational skills
- Recommending automated and manual solutions to business opportunities/problems
- Development of clear, concise documentation: process maps, presentations, recommendations, business requirements, project plans, project charters, use cases, test plans, context diagrams, wire frames or any one of a variety of artifacts required to perform my job

TOOLS

- PC Skills: Proficient in Word, EXCEL, Visio, PowerPoint, Project, SharePoint, FullShot
- Exposed to Fatwire Applications and Content Server (content management tool)
- Reporting Tools: Proficient in SQL Plus, exposed to Business Objects
- Knowledgeable and experienced with System Development Life Cycle
- Exposed to a broad range of development environments

CURRENT ROLE

The Hartford 2008 - Present Digital Commerce & Analytics/eBusiness

Assistant Director

Lead and support the development, prioritization, and execution of digital initiatives across Wealth Management lines of business. Support digital projects both strategic and tactical in nature.

- Special Achievement Award recipient; Re-engineered the prospectus management process which included the consolidation, storage and management of prospectus files used for electronic delivery and presentment. Guided this cross line of business project from problem definition through implementation, defined 'as-is' and 'to-be' processes, collaborated with business areas to improve and implement new workflows, elicited and documented requirements, contributed to the development of test plans and supported the implementation. Implemented quality controls and monitored process.
- Analyzed, presented and recommended future program direction for storage and electronic presentment of public documents.
- Managed relationship with Canadian partner. Led IT and eBusiness teams in the redesign of Canada's secured advisor web site. Facilitated and elicited business requirements, managed resources, dates and budget. Worked with partners to define audience segments, created a strategy and three year road map.
- Authored and implemented several templates to bring consistency to repeatable processes.
- Lead analyst on effort to improve the existing security functionality for user log-in, password reset and user lockout. Collaborated with business and IT partners as well as Information Protection.
 Defined new analytics to be tracked by Adobe Insight and delivered enhanced functionality which reduced the lockout rate and calls to the service center.

- Establish and foster relationships with business sponsors, owners and subject matter experts.
- Partner and align activities with supporting entities such as Customer Experience, Email Marketing (Exact Target), Customer Analytics (Adobe Insight), Strategic Initiatives, Marketing, Legal Service Center, IT.
- Scope and negotiate deliverables from initial requirements to implementation.
- Define key measures for understanding and analyzing performance.

WORK HISTORY

Hartford Life, Operations and Technology, Windsor, Connecticut IT Senior Business Consultant/Project Manager

1996 - 2008

- Led a team of four business analysts on a significant project to rewrite a mission critical pricing, trade and record keeping system used for The Hartford's equity funds. Guided team through the analysis and requirement phases. Teamed with business partners to define and develop business requirements, use cases, and business workflows. Authored and maintained traceability matrices for managing requirements. Worked with in-house and off-shore design teams.
- Lead Business Analyst on development of a public website for Hartford Life financial products. Developed wireframes, participated in RFP proposals, collaborated with business partners, documented requirements, provided input to charter and scope, managed content inventory, developed test plans, executed tests, performed demos, and performed post implementation review.
- Lead Business Analyst in the analysis and implementation of a content management application used to add and maintain web content on the public website. Developed procedures, managed, trained and supported business partners on the content management tool (Fatwire).
- Project Manager responsible for certification of 26 applications in support of Year 2000 compliance activities. Guided and prepared application owners for the corporate certification.

Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance Company

1986 to 1996

IT Senior Business Analyst, Hartford, Connecticut

- Supported Agents Recognition, Agents Contracting and Licensing and New Products.
- Lead and participated in several projects providing support in both a project management and business analyst capacity.
- Supported production maintenance initiatives.
- Facilitated requirement sessions
- Elicited and developed functional and non-functional requirements.
- Developed procedures and performed training.

ACHIEVEMENT AWARD

Special Achievement Award Recipient; 2009

Re-engineered a Prospectus Storage & Presentment Process

- Delivered in an aggressive three month timeframe for less than \$60,000
- Reduced compliance issues by 90%

CERTIFICATIONS

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt (The Hartford)

EDUCATION

Central Connecticut State University, New Britain, CT; Bachelor of Science in Accounting George Washington University, Washington, D.C.; Masters Certificate in Project Management B2T; Business Analyst Associate Certificate